Guide to Victor Riesel Papers TAM.170
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Victor Riesel Papers
1929-1994
1940-1980
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
Riesel, Victor.
Riesel, Evelyn
Riesel, Michael R.
TAM.170
13.75 Linear Feet in 25 manuscript boxes, one record carton, and one folder.
Victor Riesel (1917-1995) was born in New York and was a nationally syndicated labor journalist and an advisor to labor leaders and politicians. In 1946, he began his syndicated daily labor column, which appeared in hundreds of newspapers over the next three decades. Riesel traveled widely and in later years his politics became more conservative. By the early 1970s, he had become an advisor to the Nixon administration on labor matters. The collection includes scrapbooks, clippings, photographs and correspondence with labor leaders, political leaders and government officials, fellow journalists, and his friends and political associates. Prominent individuals include: Allen Dulles, Sidney Hook, J. Edgar Hoover, Hubert Humphrey, Richard Nixon, and Budd Schulberg among others.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Evelyn Riesel in 1995. The accession numbers associated with this gift are 1995.001 and 1995.017.
Arrangement
Organized into four series, further arranged into subseries:
Series I: Biographical
Subseries A: Diaries
Subseries B: Other Autobiographical Material
Series II: Correspondence
Subseries A: General
Subseries B: Addendum
Subseries C: Friendlies
Subseries D: Correspondence-Government
Subseries E: Correspondence-Journalism Career
Subseries F: Correspondence-Guest Columnists
Subseries G: Correspondence-Syndicated Column
Series III: Writings, Topical Files, and Research Materials
Subseries A: Scrapbooks (Riesel articles and columns)
Subseries B: Newspaper Clippings (by and about Riesel)
Subseries C: Other Writings by Riesel
Subseries D: Communism in Hollywood
Subseries E: Topical Files
Series IV: Photographs and Nonprint Materials
Folders are arranged alphabetically by subject/author heading within each series.
Biographical / Historical
Victor Riesel (1917-1995) was a nationally syndicated labor journalist, and an advisor to labor leaders and politicians. A product of New York's Lower East Side Jewish community, Riesel graduated from City College, and from its progressive political milieu to become a knowledgeable and militantly anti-communist social democrat. After work for a news service and writing for various publications, including a stint as managing editor of the New Leader (a social democratic weekly), in 1946 he began his syndicated daily labor column, which appeared in hundreds of newspapers over the next three decades. He also appeared regularly on radio and television. His exposure of labor racketeers is thought to have led to his blinding in 1956, by a man who flung acid into his eyes. Riesel traveled to some fifty countries, interviewing their labor and political leaders. Riesel's politics became more conservative, and in the early 1970s he became an unofficial, but important advisor to the Nixon administration on labor matters and on Republican outreach to the labor community and to white working class voters, meeting with cabinet level officials.
Scope and Content Note
This collection contains personal and professional materials documenting the life of Victor Riesel. The collection contains diaries, scrapbooks, and other materials regarding personal matters and trips taken by Riesel, as well as a significant amount of materials relating to the acid attack. The majority of the collection is made up of the correspondence with colleagues of Riesel, labor leaders, journalists, government officials, and other individuals, often on his articles and columns. The rest of the collection contains clippings and articles of his writings, as well as two unpublished manuscripts. It also contains photographs of Riesel with individuals and other labor groups and leaders.
Separated Material
The collection included audiocassettes which were separated to OH 500.
Telegrams; Transcripts.; Typescripts; Memorandums.; Clippings (information artifacts); Anti-communist movements -- United States.; Diaries; Scrapbooks.; Notes.; Yearbooks; Correspondence.; United States |x Politics and government |y 1969-1974.; Third parties (United States politics) |x History |v Sources.; Labor unions and communism -- United States.; Communism and motion pictures -- United States.; Labor unions -- Corrupt practices -- United States; Working class -- United States -- Political activity.; Labor policy |z United States |x History |y 20th century.; Labor leaders.; Russell, Bertrand, 1872-1970; Riesel, Victor.; Thomas, Norman, 1884-1968; Khrushchev, Nikita Sergeevich, 1894-1971; Hook, Sidney, 1902-1989; Meany, George, 1894-1980; Hoover, J. Edgar (John Edgar), 1895-1972; Humphrey, Hubert H. (Hubert Horatio), 1911-1978; Lovestone, Jay.; Dulles, Allen Welsh, 1893-1969; Eastman, Max, 1883-1969; Goldberg, Arthur J.; Nixon, Richard M. (Richard Milhous), 1913-1994; Schulberg, Budd; Riesel, Evelyn; Riesel, Michael R.
- Series I: Biographical, 1929-1981
  Scope and Content Note
  Series I contains Riesel's high school yearbook, his diaries, clippings, telegrams regarding his blinding, materials from his various travels, biographical notes, presidential inauguration invitations, and other memorabilia.
  - Subseries A: Diaries, 1929-1981
    - Morris High School Senior Book, 1929 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1958 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1959 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1960 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1962 (Box 2, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1964 (Box 2, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 6)
    - Diary, 1968 (Box 3, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 5)
    - Diary, 1973 (Box 3, Folder 6)
    - Diary, 1974 (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Diary, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 2)
    - Diary, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 3)
    - Diary, 1977 (Box 4, Folder 4)
    - Diary, 1981 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Subseries B: Other Autobiographical Material, 1940-1974
    - (Auto-) biographical fact sheets, circa 1969-1970 (Box 5, Folder 1)
    - Brother's account of the arson Attack, circa 1956 (Box 5, Folder 2)
    - Letters and cards after acid attack, April 5-6, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 3)
    - Letters and cards after acid attack, April 7-30, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 4)
    - Letters and cards after acid attack, May-Sept, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - Mail regarding eye operation, 1973 (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - Newspaper clippings - mostly acid attack, April - June, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - Newspaper clippings - mostly acid attack, July - August, 1956 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - Newspaper clippings - mostly acid attack, October - Nov., 1956 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - Newspaper clippings - mostly acid attack, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - Transcript of ITV-Interview and Newspaper Clippings of Trip to England, 1957 (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Travel Correspondence, May-June, 1961 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - Trip to Austria, 1955 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Trip to Austria-Hungary-Poland-Great Britain-Portugal, 1974 (Box 5, Folder 14)
    - Trip to France, 1960 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Trip to France-Italy-Germany, June-Aug, 1953 (Box 6, Folder 1)
    - Trip to Germany, 1972 (Box 6, Folder 2)
    - Trip to Germany-Great Britain-Northern Ireland-Iceland, 1971 (Box 6, Folder 3)
    - Trip to Germany-Italy-France, 1957 (Box 6, Folder 4)
    - Trip to Great Britain-Romania-Greece-Italy, 1969 (Box 6, Folder 5)
    - Trip to Great Britain-Sweden-Finland-Austria-Czechoslovakia, 1966 (Box 6, Folder 6)
    - Trip to Italy-Israel-Spain-London, 1968 (Box 6, Folder 7)
    - Trip to Jamaica-British Guiana-Brazil-Venezuela-Panama-Honduras-Mexico, 1965 (Box 6, Folder 8)
    - Trip to Johannesburg-Tanzania-Congo, 1959 (Box 6, Folder 9)
    - Trip to Miami-London-Germany-Switzerland, 1975 (Box 6, Folder 10)
    - Trip to Norway-Germany-France, 1967 (Box 6, Folder 11)
    - Trip to Portugal-London, 1976 (Box 6, Folder 12)
    - Trip to Spain-Israel-Ceylon [Sri Lanka]-Taiwan-Japan-Hawaii, 1970 (Box 6, Folder 13)
    - University diploma and journalism awards, 1940-1973 (Box 6, Folder 14)
- Series II: Correspondence, 1937-1994
  Series II contains Riesel's correspondence with labor leaders, political leaders and government officials, fellow journalists, and his friends and political associates. Prominent individuals include Allen Dulles, Max Eastman, Arthur Goldberg, Sidney Hook, J. Edgar Hoover, Hubert Humphrey, Jay Lovestone, George Meany, Richard Nixon, Bertrand Russell, Budd Schulberg, and Norman Thomas.
  - Subseries A: General, 1937-1994
    - Correspondence, undated (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1937-1945 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1958 (Box 7, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1959-1963 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1968 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1969 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1970 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1971 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1972 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - Correspondence, 1973 (Box 9, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1974 (Box 9, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1975 (Box 9, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1976 (Box 9, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1980 (Box 9, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1981-1994 (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Subseries B: Addendum, 1946-1991
    - Correspondence, 1946-1950 (Box 9a, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1953 (Box 9a, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1954 (Box 9a, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1955 (Box 9a, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 9a, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1958-1962 (Box 9b, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1963-1965 (Box 9b, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1968 (Box 9b, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1969-1970 (Box 9b, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1971-1972 (Box 9b, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1973-1974 (Box 9b, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, 1975-1976 (Box 9c, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, 1977-1978 (Box 9c, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, 1979-1981 (Box 9c, Folder 3)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1983 (Box 9c, Folder 4)
    - Correspondence, 1984-1985 (Box 9c, Folder 5)
    - Correspondence, 1986-1991 (Box 9c, Folder 6)
    - Correspondence, additional, 1975-1979 (Box 9D, Folder 1)
    - Correspondence, additional, 1980-1983 (Box 9D, Folder 2)
    - Correspondence, WNEW TV, 1970-1978 (Box 9D, Folder 3)
  - Subseries C: Friendlies, 1950-1983
    - "Friendlies", undated (Box 10, Folder 1)
    - "Friendlies", 1950-1951 (Box 10, Folder 2)
    - "Friendlies", 1952 (Box 10, Folder 3)
    - "Friendlies", 1953 (Box 10, Folder 4)
    - "Friendlies", 1954-1966 (Box 10, Folder 5)
    - "Friendlies", 1967-1970 (Box 10, Folder 6)
    - "Friendlies", 1971-1973 (Box 11, Folder 1)
    - "Friendlies", 1974-1983 (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Subseries D: Correspondence - Government, 1945-1984
    - Dulles, Allen, 1959 (Box 11, Folder 3)
    - FBI, 1945-1964 (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - FBI, 1965-1973 (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - FBI, 1974-1982 (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - White House, 1954-1984 (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Subseries E: Correspondence - Journalism Career, 1943-1985
    - ABC Radio/TV, 1968-1969 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Address book, 1950s -1980s (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - American Federation of Television and Radio Artists, 1967-1978 (Box 12, Folder 3)
    - Association of Radio-TV News Analysts, 1964-1976 (Box 12, Folder 4)
    - Barrows, Jim, 1980-1983 (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Channel 5, 1971-1978 (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Contact lists New York and Washington, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
    - Dow Chemical Magazine, 1973-1976 (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Publishers, 1967-1973 (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Publishers, 1974-1976 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Publishers, 1977-1985 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Publishing contracts, 1956-1981 (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Radio, 1943-1951 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Radio/TV, 1957-1968 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Radio Broadcasts, 1968-1972 (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Trip to Africa: Newsletter and Correspondence, 1959-1960 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Trip to Europe: Newsletter and Correspondence, 1961 (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Weiss (Public Relations), 1961-1971 (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - WEVD Radio, 1965-1981 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Subseries F: Correspondence - Guest Columnists, 1960-1979
    - Guest Columnists and Travel Correspondence, 1960-1962 (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Guest Columnists and Travel Correspondence, 1963 (Box 14, Folder 5)
    - Guest Columnists, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 6)
    - Guest Columnists, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 7)
    - Guest Columnists, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 1)
    - Guest Columnists, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Guest Columnists, 1973 (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Guest Columnists, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - Guest Columnists, 1977-1979 (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - Subseries G: Correspondence - Syndicated Column, 1958-1986
    - Syndicated column, 1958-1972 (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Syndicated column, 1968-1974 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Syndicated column, 1973-1974 (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - Syndicated column, Correspondence, 1975-1977 (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Syndicated column, Correspondence, 1978-1986 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Syndicated column, typescripts, 1966-1982 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Syndicated column, typescripts, 1983-1986 (Box 16, Folder 6)
- Series III: Writings, Topical Files and Research Materials
  Series III contains scrapbooks of Riesel's columns, other writings, including two unpublished typescripts, Farmer and Labor Third Parties, and Communism in the Motion Picture Industry, a file of notes and memoranda related to Riesel's Nixon Administration activity, which document confidential White House staff and cabinet-level discussions, and the transcript of a 1959 meeting between U.S. labor leaders and Soviet Premier Nikita Khrushchev.
  - Subseries A: Scrapbooks (Riesel articles and columns), 1934-1948
    - New Leader etc., 1934-1936 (Box 16a, Folder 1)
    - Various Newspapers, Jan 1941-Feb 1948 (Box 16a, Folder 2)
    - New York Post, Nov 1941-Apr 1942 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - New York Post, Apr 1942-Nov 1943 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - New York Post, Nov 1943-Jul 1944 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - New York Post, Jul 1944-Oct 1945 (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Subseries B: Newspaper Clippings (by and about Riesel), 1933-1988
    - New York Post, Nov 1945-Apr 1947 (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Clippings, undated (Box 18, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1933-1959 (Box 18, Folder 4)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1960-1969 (Box 19, Folder 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1970-1977 (Box 19, Folder 2)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1978-1988 (Box 19, Folder 3)
    - Newspaper Columns ("Inside Labor") (I), Feb 1976-Apr 1976 (Box 19, Folder 3a)
    - Newspaper Columns ("Inside Labor") (II), Feb 1976-Apr 1976 (Box 19, Folder 4)
  - Subseries C: Other Writings by Riesel, 1939-1984
    - Adenauer, Konrad - Interview, 1957 (Box 19, Folder 4a)
    - Attacks on the State Department (typescript), 1951 (Box 19, Folder 5)
    - CBC-Interview with Riesel, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 6)
    - Conversations - Transcripts?, 1958 (Box 19, Folder 7)
    - Farmer and Labor 3rd Parties (typescript), 1940 (Box 19, Folder 8)
    - Files Indices, circa 1975-1984 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Gorman of the Amalgamated (typescript), 1957 (Box 19, Folder 10)
    - "Inside Labor" typescripts, 1980-1986 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Memos and Notes, 1939-1969 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Memos and Notes, 1970-1976 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Memos and Notes, 1977-1986 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Miscellaneous, 1940-1949 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - "My War with the Mob" Pulitzer prize nomination, 1956 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Notebook, 1959 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Notes for Jewish Lectures, 1969-1971 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Press Conference with General Electric, 1978 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Riesel Speech to Associated Equipment Distributors, 1972 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - "Ten Men Can Defeat America" - typescript, circa 1956 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Subseries D: Communism in Hollywood, 1951-1960
    - Communism in Hollywood (notes and research materials), 1951-1952 (Box 21, Folder 6)
    - Communism in Hollywood (notes and research materials), 1952 (Box 21, Folder 7)
    - Communism in Hollywood (notes and research materials), 1952 (Box 21, Folder 8)
    - Communism in Hollywood (notes and research materials), 1953 (Box 21, Folder 9)
    - Communism in the Motion Picture Industry (typescript), 1960 (Box 22, Folder 1)
  - Subseries E: Topical Files, 1945-1988
    - Anti-Semitism issues, 1968-1969 (Box 22, Folder 2)
    - Carpenters, circa 1960 (Box 22, Folder 3)
    - Bonitati, Robert, 1981-1983 (Box 22, Folder 4)
    - Conference on Technological Change and Human Development, Jerusalem, 1969 (Box 22, Folder 5)
    - Council on Foreign Relations, 1967-1981 (Box 22, Folder 6)
    - Court Case: Anthony Anastasio v. Victor Riesel, 1952 (Box 22, Folder 7)
    - Democratic Convention, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 8)
    - Examination and Comparison of Signatures: Richard/Dick Pastor, 1958 (Box 22, Folder 9)
    - Hall, Paul, 1960-1980 (Box 22, Folder 10)
    - Hoffa, James, 1958-1975 (Box 22, Folder 11)
    - Khrushchev and Mikoyan meetings with Reuther et al., 1959 (Box 22, Folder 12)
    - Korshak, Sidney, 1976 (Box 22, Folder 13)
    - Labor and the Cater Administration, 1976-1980 (Box 22, Folder 14)
    - Labor Critique of McGovern, 1972 (Box 22, Folder 15)
    - Labor News - Miscellaneous, 1986-1988 (Box 22, Folder 16)
    - Labor Organization Annual Reports, 1964-1971 (Box 23, Folder 1)
    - Meat Packing Union, 1967 (Box 23, Folder 2)
    - Meir, Golda article, 1970 (Box 23, Folder 3)
    - Mine, Mill Workers Prosecution, 1956-1962 (Box 23, Folder 4)
    - National Health Insurance, 1979 (Box 23, Folder 5)
    - National Labor Management Conference, 1945 (Box 23, Folder 6)
    - Nixon File - Memos, 1960-1969 (Box 23, Folder 7)
    - Nixon File - Memos, 1970-1972 (Box 23, Folder 8)
    - Nixon File - Memos, 1973-1978 (Box 23, Folder 9)
    - Notes: Communism, 1948-1977 (Box 24, Folder 1)
    - Organized crime, 1963-1981 (Box 24, Folder 2)
    - Pegler, Westbrook David, 1947-1963 (Box 24, Folder 3)
    - Posner, Herman, 1959-1960 (Box 24, Folder 4)
    - President's Committee on Employment for the Handicapped, 1970-1978 (Box 24, Folder 5)
    - Reagan and American Labor - Interview with Riesel, undated (Box 24, Folder 6)
    - Reagan - White House Memos, 1983-1985 (Box 24, Folder 7)
    - Rockefeller File, 1968-1975 (Box 24, Folder 8)
    - Ruby, Jack, 1976-1983 (Box 24, Folder 8a)
    - Scotto, Anthony, 1966-1979 (Box 24, Folder 9)
    - Scotto, Anthony, 1979-1982 (Box 24, Folder 10)
    - Screen Actors Guild, 1980-1985 (Box 24, Folder 10a)
    - "Show business tribute to Harold G. Gibbons", 1969 (Box 24, Folder 11)
    - Sokolsky, George, 1953-1957 (Box 24, Folder 12)
    - Steel Industry, 1983 (Box 24, Folder 13)
    - United Nations, San Francisco, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 0.1)
    - "The International Jewelry Workers Union - A History of Betrayal", 1958 (Box 25, Folder 1)
    - "Trade Unionism in the United States" by John A. Fitch, 1945 (Box 25, Folder 2)
    - Transcript of Hearings before the Committee to investigate charges against International Union of Mine, Mill, and Smelter Workers., 1950 (Box 25, Folder 3)
- Series IV: Photographs and Nonprint Materials, 1945-1979
  This series contains photographs and other nonprint materials. It includes many photographs of Riesel with labor leaders and other well known individuals. Many of these photographs are contained in scrapbooks, sometimes accompanied with clippings or captions. There are also some images of Riesel directly after the acid attack. The series also contains audographs, posters, booklets, a scapular, a press pass, and a map of Israel.
  - Victor Riesel Portraits, undated (Box 26)
  - Riesel with Charlton Heston, Mike Quill, Bruno Kreisky, and George Meany, 1961-1974 (Box 26)
  - Dennis the Menace Comics, 1976 (Box 26)
  - Monitored Pictures and Script of Interview with American Journalist-Victor Riesel on ITV's Special News Magazine Programme "This Week", Aug 23, 1957 (Box 26)
  - Photographs of Riesel with Steelworkers Union organizers, Luggage Workers, and others, 1957-1958 (Box 26)
  - FBI Visit Photographs, 1975 (Box 26)
  - Portraits of Riesel, David Basnett, Lord Alec Douglas Home, Jimmy Carter, George Meany, and others, 1967-1977 (Box 26)
  - Press Pass, Green Scapular, Map of Israel, 1968 (Box 26)
  - Three Audographs, undated (Box 26)
  - Photographs of Riesel and other individuals, including Chief Albert Luthuli, Governor Nelson Rockefeller, President of Taiwan Chiang Ching-Kuo, Prime Minister Harold Wilson at the Automation House Dinner, Harry Van Arsdale (President of the Central Labor Council), Al Shanker (President of the Teachers Union), Willy Brandt of Germany at a Waldorf Dinner, and Evelyn Riesel. There is also a photograph of Riesel at the Berlin Wall., 1959-1978 (Box 26)
  - Nobel Peace Prize booklet, Solidarnosc Poster, National Employ the Handicapped Week Proclamation, 1969, 1973 (Box 26)
  - Brown Album, 1954-1963 (Box 26)
    The album contains loose photographs of Venice, Victor Riesel, Pat Touchae, Labor Secretary Arthur Goldberg, Harry Van Arsdale, Institute of Management Executive Seminar, 1963 Newspaper Strike, Associated General Contractors of America, Riesel in the hospital after the acid attack, assorted newspaper editors, other unlabelled group and individual photographs. There is also a certificate of appointment and clippings.
  - Red Album, 1951-1960 (Box 26)
    This album contains photographs of Riesel in Nairobi, Kenya airport; in Omaha, Nebraska; and with many different individuals and organizations including Dr. C.C. Humphreys and his wife; Dr. O.W. Hyman; A.E. Hohenberg; Louis Catapane; Alexander Cashin; George M. Barker; American Heart Association; Binghamton University lecture; Theatrical Square Club; Raymond Hilliard; Meet the Press with Charles Sawyer (Secretary of Commerce); Samuel and Martha Downes Fuller; National Council of Industrial Management Clubs; Greater Lawrence (Massachusetts) Junior Chamber of Commerce; G.E. Security Conference; and the 10th Anniversary of Israel cocktail party.
    Many photographs were taken by Daniel Nilva.
  - Blue Album, 1945-1968 (Box 26)
    This album contains photographs of Riesel's visit to the US Naval Training Center and Israel. It also contains photographs of Riesel with individuals and organizations, including David Dubinsky, the Jewish Labor Committee, Burt Ross, Dave Siegel, Harry Quinn, Meet the Press, Hess E. Fritz, and Admiral M. Martin.
  - "Ten Men Who Could Paralyze America: A Sell-Out of Members by Mine, Mill Exposed!!!" Poster; "My War with the Mob" Poster; and Photographs of Riesel after the acid attack and a photograph of Riesel, Evelyn Riesel, and William H. Webster, 1957-1970s (Box Shared Tamiment OS006)